A Guide to the James Whitcomb Riley Collection
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #7133-k
James Whitcomb Riley Collection 1876-1912
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
7133-k
ca. 65 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Purchase [1970 July 15] 1970 August 18
Item Listing
- Manuscripts
  - Story, "The Bad Little Boy's Version of Jack the Giant-Killer", ca. 1876-1902; AMsS, 2 p.
  - "The Book of Joyous Children", ca. 1876-1902; Corrected proof, 1 p.
  - Poem, "A Dream of Autumn", ca. 1876-1902; AMsS, 3 p.
  - Poem, "The Dusk", ca. 1876-1902; AMsS, 1 p.
  - Poem, "Ere I went Mad", ca. 1876-1902; AMs, 1 p.
  - Poem, "From a Balloon", ca. 1876-1902; AMs, 2 p.
  - Poem, "John Boyle O'Reilly. Sepulture-Boston, Aug. 13-1890", ca. 1890; AMsS, 1 p.
  - Poem, "The Land of Used to Be", ca. 1876-1902; AMsS, 1 p.
  - Poem, "Love's Rival", ca. 1876-1902; AMsS, 1 p.
  - Poem, "My Dancin' Days is Over", ca. 1876-1902; TMsS, 1 p.
  - Poem, "A Parting", ca. 1876-1902; AMs, 1 p.
  - Poem, "A Tress of Hair", ca. 1876-1902; AMs, 1 p.
  - Poem, "The Used To Be", ca. 1876-1902; AMsS, 2 p.
  - "Waitin' for the Cat to Die", ca. 1876-1902; AMsS, 3 p.
  - "The Tunes of Other Days," on verso of "Your Violin," Poem, ca. 1876-1902; AMs, 1 p.
  - "Your Violin," verso of poem above, ca. 1876-1902; AMsS, 1 p.
- Letters
  - Clara E. Laughlin to James Whitcomb Riley, 1897 Dec 17; ALS, 5 p. w/env
  - Clara E. Laughlin to James Whitcomb Riley, 1897 Dec 23; ALS, 1 p. w/env
  - Clara E. Laughlin to James Whitcomb Riley, 1898 Jan 18; ALS, 1 p.
  - Clara E. Laughlin to James Whitcomb Riley, 1898 Feb 2; ALS, 4 p. w/env
  - Clara E. Laughlin to James Whitcomb Riley, 1898 Apr 5; ALS, 3 p. w/env
  - Clara E. Laughlin to James Whitcomb Riley, 1898 Apr 30; ALS, 3 p. w/env
  - Clara E. Laughlin to James Whitcomb Riley, 1898 May 7; ALS, 4 p. w/env
  - Clara E. Laughlin to James Whitcomb Riley, 1898 May 24; ALS, 4 p. w/env
  - Clara E. Laughlin to James Whitcomb Riley, w/pasted clipping, 1898 Aug 2; ALS, 2 p. w/env
  - Clara E. Laughlin to James Whitcomb Riley, 1898 Aug 18; ALS, 1 p. w/env
  - Clara E. Laughlin to James Whitcomb Riley, 1898 Aug 27; ALS, 2 p. w/env
  - Clara E. Laughlin to James Whitcomb Riley, w/telegram, 1898 Sep 9; ALS, 3 p. w/env
  - Clara E. Laughlin to James Whitcomb Riley, 1898 Sep 12; ALS, 1 p. w/env
  - Clara E. Laughlin to James Whitcomb Riley, w/AL poem, 1898 Oct 6; ALS, 4 p. w/env
  - Clara E. Laughlin to James Whitcomb Riley, 1898 Oct 11; ALS, 1 p. w/env
  - Clara E. Laughlin to James Whitcomb Riley, 1898 Dec 3; ALS, 3 p. w/env
  - Clara E. Laughlin to James Whitcomb Riley, 1898 Dec 12; ALS, 4 p. w/env
  - Clara E. Laughlin to James Whitcomb Riley, 1898 Dec 30; ALS, 2 p.
  - Curts & Jennings to Editor of "The Interior", 1899 Jan 13; TL, 1 p.
  - Clara E. Laughlin to James Whitcomb Riley, 1899 Jan 13; ALS, 4 p. w/env
  - Clara E. Laughlin to James Whitcomb Riley, 1899 Jan 16; ALS, 3 p. w/env
  - Clara E. Laughlin to James Whitcomb Riley, 1899 Jan 21; ALS, 1 p. w/env
  - Clara E. Laughlin to James Whitcomb Riley, 1899 Jan 23; ALS, 1 p. w/env
  - Clara E. Laughlin to James Whitcomb Riley, 1899 Jan 27; ALS, 1 p. w/env
  - Clara E. Laughlin to James Whitcomb Riley, 1899 Jan 28; ALS, 6 p. w/env
  - Clara E. Laughlin to James Whitcomb Riley, 1899 Feb 1; ALS, 3 p. w/env
  - Clara E. Laughlin to James Whitcomb Riley, 1899 Apr 25; ALS, 1 p. w/env
  - Clara E. Laughlin to James Whitcomb Riley, 1899 Aug 8; ALS, 2 p. w/env
  - Clara E. Laughlin to James Whitcomb Riley, 1899 Aug 9; ALS, 1 p. w/env
  - Clara E. Laughlin to James Whitcomb Riley, 1899 Oct 6; ALS, 1 p. w/env
  - Henry Van Dyke to James Whitcomb Riley, 1901 Feb 18; ALS, 3 p. w/env
  - Henry Van Dyke to James Whitcomb Riley, 1901 Oct 5; ALS, 3 p. w/env
  - Henry Van Dyke to James Whitcomb Riley, 1903 Apr 4; ALS, 3 p. w/env
  - Clara E. Laughlin under pseudonym of "Constance Glendower" to James Whitcomb Riley under pseudonym of "Hon. Harold Ash", 1904 Oct 31; ALS, 3 p.
  - Henry Van Dyke to James Whitcomb Riley, 1904 Dec 20; ALS, 2 p. w/env
  - "Constance Glendower" [i.e. Clara E. Laughlin] to James Whitcomb Riley, 1905 Dec 6; ALS, 1 p. w/env
  - Clara E. Laughlin to James Whitcomb Riley, 1906 May 28; ALS, 1 p. w/env
  - Clara E. Laughlin to James Whitcomb Riley, 1906 Sep 3; ALS, 2 p. w/env
  - Clara E. Laughlin to James Whitcomb Riley, w/American Express form, 1906 Sep 7; ALS, 1 p. w/env
  - Clara E. Laughlin to James Whitcomb Riley, 1906 Sep 12; ALS, 1 p. w/env
  - Clara E. Laughlin to James Whitcomb Riley, 1906 Sep 26; ALS, 2 p. w/env
  - Clara E. Laughlin to James Whitcomb Riley, 1906 Sep 28; ALS, 2 p. w/env
  - Clara E. Laughlin to James Whitcomb Riley, 1906 Nov 16; ALS, 2 p. w/env
  - Henry Van Dyke to James Whitcomb Riley, 1907 Mar 12; ALS, 1 p. w/env
  - Clara E. Laughlin to James Whitcomb Riley, 1907 Mar 30; ALS, 2 p. w/env
  - Henry Van Dyke to James Whitcomb Riley, 1907 Nov 21; ALS, 1 p. w/env
  - Clara E. Laughlin to James Whitcomb Riley, 1912 Oct 6; ALS, 2 p. w/env